{
    "name": "U.S. Presidents",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "Who was the first president of the United States?",
            "type": "multi",
            "correct": "George Washington",
            "answers": [
                "George Washington",
                "Jon Adams",
                "Thomas Jefferson",
                "James Madison"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Which president established Thanksgiving as a national holiday?",
            "type": "multi",
            "correct": "Abraham Lincoln",
            "answers": [
                "Abraham Lincoln",
                "James Madison",
                "Barack Obama",
                "Ulysses S. Grant"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Which president led the Union Armies to victory over the Confederacy in the American Civil War?",
            "type": "multi",
            "correct": "Ulysses S. Grant",
            "answers": [
                "Ulysses S. Grant",
                "George Washington",
                "Abraham Lincoln",
                "James Madison"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Which president was assassinated only 200 days into his presidency?",
            "type": "multi",
            "correct": "James A. Garfield",
            "answers": [
                "James A. Garfield",
                "Jon Kennedy",
                "Herbert Hoover",
                "John Tyler"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Which president led the United States into World War I?",
            "type": "multi",
            "correct": "Woodrow Wilson",
            "answers": [
                "Woodrow Wilson",
                "James K. Polk",
                "John Quincy Adams",
                "Ulysses S. Grant"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Which president was known as the country's \"food czar\"?",
            "type": "multi",
            "correct": "Herbert Hoover",
            "answers": [
                "Herbert Hoover",
                "Grover Cleveland",
                "Lyndon B. Johnson",
                "Jimmy Carter"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Which president made the decision to use the atomic bomb against Japan?",
            "type": "multi",
            "correct": "Harry S. Truman",
            "answers": [
                "Harry S. Truman",
                "Franklin D. Roosevelt",
                "William McKinley",
                "Warren G. Harding"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Which president spoke English as a second language?",
            "type": "multi",
            "correct": "Martin Van Buren",
            "answers": [
                "Martin Van Buren",
                "William Henry Harrison",
                "Grover Cleveland",
                "William Howard Taft"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Which president died 31 days after his innaguration?",
            "type": "multi",
            "correct": "William Henry Harrison",
            "answers": [
                "William Henry Harrison",
                "James K. Polk",
                "Robert Kennedy",
                "Zachary Taylor"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was the first president to have his veto of legislation overridden by Congress?",
            "type": "multi",
            "correct": "John Tyler",
            "answers": [
                "John Tyler",
                "Harry S. Truman",
                "Richard Nixon",
                "Bill Clinton"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Which president had 15 kids?",
            "type": "multi",
            "correct": "John Tyler",
            "answers": [
                "John Tyler",
                "Millard Fillmore",
                "Franklin Pierce",
                "Jon Kennedy"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Which president is known for acquiring more than a million square miles of western territory  including California, Nevada, Utah, Arizona, New Mexico, and parts of Colorado and Wyoming?",
            "type": "multi",
            "correct": "James K. Polk",
            "answers": [
                "James K. Polk",
                "James Buchanan",
                "Abraham Lincoln",
                "Andrew Johnson"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Which president died of Cholera less than 2 years in office?",
            "type": "multi",
            "correct": "Zachary Taylor",
            "answers": [
                "Zachary Taylor",
                "Millard Fillmore",
                "Franklin Pierce",
                "James Buchanan"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was the last to be a Whig party president?",
            "type": "multi",
            "correct": "Millard Fillmore",
            "answers": [
                "Millard Fillmore",
                "William Henry Harrison",
                "Rutherford B. Hayes",
                "John Adams"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was the only Federalist party president?",
            "type": "multi",
            "correct": "John Adams",
            "answers": [
                "John Adams",
                "Thomas Jefferson",
                "James Madison",
                "John Quincy Adams"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Which president-elect lost their 11 year old son due to train derailment?",
            "type": "multi",
            "correct": "Franklin Pierce",
            "answers": [
                "Franklin Pierce",
                "Theodore Roosevelt",
                "Franklin D. Roosevelt",
                "Warren G. Harding"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Which president was ridiculed for his handling of the Fort Sumter crisis?",
            "type": "multi",
            "correct": "James Buchanan",
            "answers": [
                "James Buchanan",
                "Rutherford B. Hayes",
                "John Tyler",
                "Abraham Lincoln"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Which president issued the Emancipation Proclamation that freed slaves within the Confederacy?",
            "type": "multi",
            "correct": "Abraham Lincoln",
            "answers": [
                "Abraham Lincoln",
                "Ulysses S. Grant",
                "George Washington",
                "Andrew Jackson"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was the first president to be impeached by the House of Representatives?",
            "type": "multi",
            "correct": "Andrew Johnson",
            "answers": [
                "Andrew Johnson",
                "Bill Clinton",
                "Donald Trump",
                "Richard Nixon"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "What president led the Union Armies to victory in the American Civil war and later became the 18th president?",
            "type": "multi",
            "correct": "Ulysses S. Grant",
            "answers": [
                "Ulysses S. Grant",
                "Abraham Lincoln",
                "James Madison",
                "George Washington"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Which president led the end of Reconstruction and returned the South to \"home rule\"?",
            "type": "multi",
            "correct": "Rutherford B. Hayes",
            "answers": [
                "Rutherford B. Hayes",
                "Ulysses S. Grant",
                "Abraham Lincoln",
                "James A. Garfield"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Which president who was assassinated published a proof of the Pythagorean theorem?",
            "type": "multi",
            "correct": "James A. Garfield",
            "answers": [
                "James A. Garfield",
                "Millard Fillmore",
                "Woodrow Wilson",
                "Robert Kennedy"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Which president was the replacement of the assassinated James Garfield?",
            "type": "multi",
            "correct": "Chester A. Arthur",
            "answers": [
                "Chester A. Arthur",
                "Grover Cleveland",
                "Rutherford B. Hayes",
                "Ulysses S. Grant"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Which president who was the first Democrat elected after the Civil War also was the first president to serve two non-consecutive term?",
            "type": "multi",
            "correct": "Grover Cleveland",
            "answers": [
                "Grover Cleveland",
                "William McKinley",
                "Benjamin Harrison",
                "William McKinley"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Which president was responsible for annexing the Republic of Hawaii, and purchasing the Philippines, Guam and Puerto Rico?",
            "type": "multi",
            "correct": "William McKinley",
            "answers": [
                "William McKinley",
                "Theodore Roosevelt",
                "Benjamin Harrison",
                "Chester A. Arthur"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Under which president did congress pass the Sherman Antitrust Act of 1890 which was the first federal law to regulate corporations and prevent monopolies?",
            "type": "multi",
            "correct": "Benjamin Harrison",
            "answers": [
                "Benjamin Harrison",
                "Grover Cleveland",
                "William McKinley",
                "William Howard Taft"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Which president was the first American to ever win a Nobel Prize?",
            "type": "multi",
            "correct": "Theodore Roosevelt",
            "answers": [
                "Theodore Roosevelt",
                "Ronald Reagan",
                "George Washington",
                "Abraham Lincoln"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Which president also served as Chief Justice of the United States?",
            "type": "multi",
            "correct": "William Howard Taft",
            "answers": [
                "William Howard Taft",
                "Chester A. Arthur",
                "Andrew Johnson",
                "James Madison"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Which president signed the first major federal governmen social welfare legislation the Sheppardâ€“Towner Maternity Act?",
            "type": "multi",
            "correct": "Warren G. Harding",
            "answers": [
                "Warren G. Harding",
                "Calvin Coolidge",
                "Herbert Hoover",
                "Franklin D. Roosevelt"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Which president signed the Indian Citizenship Act of 1924 granting U.S. citizenship to all Native Americans?",
            "type": "multi",
            "correct": "Calvin Coolidge",
            "answers": [
                "Calvin Coolidge",
                "Herbert Hoover",
                "Warren G. Harding",
                "Franklin D. Roosevelt"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was the only president to server more than two terms?",
            "type": "multi",
            "correct": "Franklin D. Roosevelt",
            "answers": [
                "Franklin D. Roosevelt",
                "Harry S. Truman",
                "Dwight D. Eisenhower",
                "Calvin Coolidge"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Which president promised the American people a New Deal during the great depression?",
            "type": "multi",
            "correct": "Franklin D. Roosevelt",
            "answers": [
                "Franklin D. Roosevelt",
                "Harry S. Truman",
                "Woodrow Wilson",
                "Andrew Johnson"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Which president led the United States into World War 2?",
            "type": "multi",
            "correct": "Franklin D. Roosevelt ",
            "answers": [
                "Franklin D. Roosevelt ",
                "Harry S. Truman",
                "Dwight D. Eisenhower",
                "Herbert Hoover"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Which president led the United States into World War 1?",
            "type": "multi",
            "correct": "Woodrow Wilson",
            "answers": [
                "Woodrow Wilson",
                "Franklin D. Roosevelt ",
                "Dwight D. Eisenhower",
                "Harry S. Truman"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Which president authroized the use of the Atomic Bomb?",
            "type": "multi",
            "correct": "Harry S. Truman",
            "answers": [
                "Harry S. Truman",
                "Woodrow Wilson",
                "Franklin D. Roosevelt ",
                "Dwight D. Eisenhower"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Which president was the Supreme Commander of the troops invading France on D-Day during WW2?",
            "type": "multi",
            "correct": "Dwight D. Eisenhower",
            "answers": [
                "Dwight D. Eisenhower",
                "Franklin D. Roosevelt ",
                "Harry S. Truman",
                "Woodrow Wilson"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Which president wrote \"Profiles in Courage\" and won the Pulitzer Prize in history?",
            "type": "multi",
            "correct": "John F. Kennedy",
            "answers": [
                "John F. Kennedy",
                "Lyndon B. Johnson",
                "Franklin D. Roosevelt ",
                "Harry S. Truman"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Which president made the Apollo program a national priority?",
            "type": "multi",
            "correct": "Lyndon B. Johnson",
            "answers": [
                "Lyndon B. Johnson",
                "John F. Kennedy",
                "Richard Nixon",
                "Gerald Ford"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Which president escalated involvement in the Vietnam War?",
            "type": "multi",
            "correct": "Lyndon B. Johnson",
            "answers": [
                "Lyndon B. Johnson",
                "George Bush",
                "Bill Clinton",
                "Gerald Ford"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Which president  signed the Social Security Amendments of 1965, leading to Medicare and Medicaid?",
            "type": "multi",
            "correct": "Lyndon B. Johnson",
            "answers": [
                "Lyndon B. Johnson",
                "Gerald Ford",
                "Richard Nixon",
                "Harry S. Truman"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Under which president were the Civil Rights Act of 1964, the Voting Rights Act of 1965, and the Civil Rights Act of 1968 bills signed?",
            "type": "multi",
            "correct": "Lyndon B. Johnson",
            "answers": [
                "Lyndon B. Johnson",
                "Gerald Ford",
                "Harry S. Truman",
                "Richard Nixon"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Which president resigned over the watergate scandal?",
            "type": "multi",
            "correct": "Richard Nixon",
            "answers": [
                "Richard Nixon",
                "Harry S. Truman",
                "Gerald Ford",
                "Bill Clinton"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was the first vice president chosen under the Twenty-fifth Amendment?",
            "type": "multi",
            "correct": "Gerald R. Ford",
            "answers": [
                "Gerald R. Ford",
                "Richard Nixon",
                "Bill Clinton",
                "Donald Trump"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Which president created the Department of Energy to research wind and solar power?",
            "type": "multi",
            "correct": "Jimmy Carter",
            "answers": [
                "Jimmy Carter",
                "Bill Clinton",
                "Barack Obama",
                "George W. Bush"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Which president was a Hollywood actor?",
            "type": "multi",
            "correct": "Ronald Reagan",
            "answers": [
                "Ronald Reagan",
                "Bill Clinton",
                "Jimmy Carter",
                "George W. Bush"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Which president oversaw the end of the Cold War?",
            "type": "multi",
            "correct": "George W. Bush",
            "answers": [
                "George W. Bush",
                "Bill Clinton",
                "Ronald Reagan",
                "Jimmy Carter"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Which president signed the North American Free Trade Agreement into law? ",
            "type": "multi",
            "correct": "Bill Clinton",
            "answers": [
                "Bill Clinton",
                "Donald Trump",
                "Ronald Reagan",
                "Jimmy Carter"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was the president during September 11, 2001?",
            "type": "multi",
            "correct": "George W. Bush",
            "answers": [
                "George W. Bush",
                "Bill Clinton",
                "George H. W. Bush",
                "Barack Obama"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Which president was responsible for the Affordable Care Act (ACA)?",
            "type": "multi",
            "correct": "Barack Obama",
            "answers": [
                "Barack Obama",
                "Bill Clinton",
                "George W. Bush",
                "Ronald Reagan"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Who was the only president that was impeached multiple times?",
            "type": "multi",
            "correct": "Donald Trump",
            "answers": [
                "Donald Trump",
                "Bill Clinton",
                "Andrew Jackson",
                "Ronald Reagan"
            ]
        },
        {
            "question": "Which president precided over the end of military involvement in Afghanistan? ",
            "type": "multi",
            "correct": "Joe Biden",
            "answers": [
                "Joe Biden",
                "George W. Bush",
                "Bill Clinton",
                "Barack Obama"
            ]
        }
    ]
}